유니티의 오디오 컴포넌트는 게임 내에서
The Audio Listener component is the equivalent
당신의 귀와 같은 역할을 합니다.
of your ears in the game.
오디오 컴포넌트는 Game World 안에서
It receives, or listens, to audio sources
오디오 소스를 듣습니다.
that are in the game world.
오디오 동작의 조절 / 제어는
The control of the audio's behaviour is done on
오디오 소스 컴포넌트에서 수행이 되기 때문에
the audio source component
오디오 리스너는 아무런 설정항목이 없습니다.
and therefore the listener itself has no settings.
씬 내부의 카메라 오브젝트는 오디오 리스너를 기본으로 갖고 있습니다.
This is attached to a camera in your scene by default
하지만 오디오 리스너는 다른 오브젝트에 위치할 수 있습니다.
but can be placed on any object.
종종 오디오 리스너는 캐릭터에 추가되기도 합니다.
Often this is attached to a character
결정적으로 오디오 리스너는 그 기능을 제대로 수행하기 위해서
and crucially there can be only one listener
씬 내에 하나만 존재해야 합니다.
per scene in order for it to function correctly.
오디오 미리보기(audio preview) 옵션을 활성화 한 상태로
You can test an audio listener from any position in the world
Game World 내에서 씬 카메라의 위치를 이동시켜 가면서
by moving the scene camera around
오디오 리스너를 테스트 해볼 수 있습니다.
with the audio preview toggle enabled.
이렇게 하면 해당 리스너를 직접 옮기거나
This gives you live testing of audio sources
게임을 플레이 하지 않고
in your environment without having to move
테스트를 할 수 있습니다.
the real listener or play test the game.
오디오 소스는 오디오를 재생하는 컴포넌트 입니다.
Audio sources are components that playback audio.
Game World 내에서 말하는 사람과 같다고 생각하시면 될 것 같네요.
Think of them as speakers in the game world.
이 예제에서 터빈은 오디오 클립이 있는
In this example our turbine has an audio source attached
오디오 소스 컴포넌트를 갖고 있습니다.
with the turbine audio clip that's been applied to it.
Drag & Drop 으로 오디오 클립을 간단히 할당할 수 있고,
We can assign a clip by dragging and dropping,
코드내에서 오디오 클립을 선택해 재생할 수 있습니다.+
or by using code to select a clip to play.
음소거가 가능하고, bypass 필터 효과를 줄수도 있고,
We can mute, bypass any filters,
게임이 시작되는 것과 같이 - 해당 오브젝트가 awake 동작일 때
choose whether to play this audio source on awake,
오디오를 재생할 지 결정할 수 있고,
as in - when the game begins
반복(loop)해서 재생 할지 결정할 수 있습니다.
and whether to loop the clip.
우선순위(Priority)는 0부터 255 사이의 값을 갖습니다.
Priority varies between 0 and 255,
0은 가장 높은 우선순위를 나타냅니다.
0 being the highest priority.
여러 개의 오디오 클립들이 한 번에 재생될 때
It's advisable to have music set as the highest priority
다른 오디오 클립과 겹쳐서 재생되는 것을 피해야 하는 경우,
to avoid other clips from overriding
해당 오이도 소스에 높은 우선순위를 설정하는 것이 좋습니다.
when many clips are being played at once.
볼륨은 원래의 waveform을 기준으로 해당 클립이 재생될 때의
Volume determines how loud the clip is played
소리 크기를 결정합니다.
based on it's original waveform.
Pitch는 오디오 클립의 pitch 값을 조절합니다.
Pitch controls the pitch of a clip.
여러분이 3D 사운드로 작업을 하시는 경우,
If you're working with 3D sounds
좀 더 세부적인 설정 항목들이 있습니다.
the settings are more detailed.
도플러 레벨(Doppler level)은
Doppler level defines how much the Doppler Effect
도플러 효과를 얼마나 사용할 지 결정합니다.
will be used.
도플러 효과는 오디오 리스너가
This is a perceived shift in frequency as the listener
오디오 소스에 다가가거나 지나칠 때의
or the ear in real terms
주파수 변화를 감지합니다.
is moving past the sound source.
오디오 소스에 다가가면 소리가 커지게 되고,
It will seem higher approaching it
멀어지면 소리가 작아지게 됩니다.
and lower as it moves away.
쉽게 응급차가 여러분 근처를 지나갈 때
Think of an emergency vehicle's siren as it passes you
사이렌 소리가 어떻게 변하는 지를 생각해 보시면 됩니다.
for example.
Volume roll-off 는 리스너가 오디오 소스에서 멀어질 때
Volume roll-off determines the type of roll-off
사운드에 의해 사용 되는
to be used by the sound
roll-off 효과의 타입을 결정합니다.
as the listener moves away from it.
이 값들은 logarithmic(로그 형), Linear (선형)형태가 있고,
This can be logarithmic, linear,
커브를 이용해서 수동으로 값을 줄 수 있으며,
or customised manually using a curve
보시는 것과 같이 키를 추가할 수 있습니다.
and adding keys as shown.
minimum distance(최소 거리)는 최대 볼륨으로
The minimum distance defines how close
사운드를 재생하는 거리를 결정합니다.
to play the sound at full volume.
따라서, 여러분이 3D 사운드를
So if you are designing 3D sound
use this value to make the sound source louder.
This can be adjusted using the spherical Gizmo
in the scene view.
And it works in the conjunction with the
maximum distance setting below,
which by default is set to 500 metres
and is a distance after which
the sound rolls off.
Pan level defines how truly 3D the sound is.
This defaults to 1 for 3D sound
making it fully panned when the stereo listener
is moved past it.
Spread is the control of the angle of spread
from 3D stereo to multichannel sound.
Finally for 2D sound pan can be controlled
at the bottom of the component.
As a rule elements such as music
should be set to 2D sound,
whilst diegetic sound that should be
fading realistically should be set up
as 3D and positioned accordingly.
The 2D and 3D values of a sound
are controlled by an audio clip's import settings.
When selecting a clip in the project
you will be able to see the import settings
in the inspector.
You can choose the audio format to use,
whether it should be 3D or 2D sound,
whether you want to force your stereo sound to mono,
how to load it and what compression to use.
You can also preview sound at the bottom,
choose whether to loop whilst previewing
and set the inspector to auto-play
whilst browsing through clips.